tinbu.com 2014-06-23

# TinBu LLC

| 

Welcome to the TinBu Network, owned and produced by TinBu, LLC. and its subsidiary and affiliate corporations, successors, and assigns (collectively referred to as "TinBu"). The TinBu Network consists of its owned and operated web sites, and its interactive content modules which are distributed on 3rd party web sites around the world. By using our Products and Services, you agree, without limitation or qualification, to be bound by this Privacy Policy or any other privacy or data collection policy applicable to any individual TinBu Network Web site or module, and to receive any required legal notices regarding our privacy practices through the continuous posting of a clear and conspicuous link to the current version of this Privacy Policy throughout the TinBu Network near the bottom of most pages

Please note that the TinBu Network contains links to other sites and occasionally allows other sites to be co-branded with the TinBu name. Web sites that are linked to TinBu Network sites or carry the TinBu brand for co-branding or marketing purposes may have privacy policies which differ from that of the TinBu Network. 

#### 1\. What information of yours does the TinBu Network collect?

Our goal is to become your favorite Internet destination by providing the information, services, and product offerings that are most relevant to you at our web sites or at the web sites that use TinBu data modules. To achieve this goal, the TinBu Network must collect information so we can understand what makes you different from its millions of other unique users. While you are not required to register for any services on the TinBu Network, some Products and Services may not function properly or may not be accessible unless you do.

Information collected online is usually defined as being either **anonymous** or **personally identifiable**. 

  *   
TinBu collects anonymous information, which refers to data that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. For example, TinBu collects some information each time a visitor comes to a TinBu Network site so we can improve the overall quality of the visitor's online experience. TinBu collects the visitor's IP address (e.g., whether the user is logged on from ibm.com or aol.com), referral data (e.g., the Internet address of the last Web page visited by a user before clicking over to a TinBu Network site), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on a Macintosh platform). TinBu also collects aggregate search terms from its HotBot and TinBu search services for internal reporting targeted advertising, and the TinBu 50 list of popular search terms. TinBu collects this user information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement, and targeted advertising. In addition, TinBu collects your responses to online surveys displayed on the TinBu Network; these anonymous and optional surveys will seek your opinions about the Products and Services or the advertisements displayed on the TinBu Network. You do not have to register with the TinBu Network before we can collect this anonymous information.
  *  **Personally identifiable information** refers to data that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and postal address, which may be collected in addition to the anonymous data described above. TinBu collects personal information in the following ways from different parts of its network of Web sites:
    1. **TinBu Network Registration** : When you register to use one or more sites on the TinBu Network, you provide TinBu with your name, postal address, ZIP Code, email address, birth date, gender, telephone number, occupation, marital status and other information. While not all of this data is required for our services to function, we are better able to customize your experience if you volunteer complete and accurate information. Users who complete the registration process are given a TinBu Network ID and can take full advantage of the many offerings across the TinBu Network.
    2.  **Other Registration** : In addition to registration for various services on the TinBu Network, we may ask you for personal information at other times, including when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by the TinBu Network. As described below, our co-brand partners also ask for personal information. If you purchase premium services we will ask for a valid credit card number. If you choose not to provide the requested information, the TinBu Network may not be able to offer you some of the personalized services that depend on this type of information to function
    3.  **Correspondence** : If you contact the TinBu Network, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We do not collect any email addresses of those who communicate with the TinBu Network via email. We use the information provided so that we may respond to the email.
TinBu reserves the right to collect certain information and store it in connection with your account. This information includes information about the different sites that you visit within the TinBu Network as well as the time and frequency at which you visit them. This information also includes the content that you transmit or post on the TinBu Network. For further information about TinBu's policy on maintaining transmitted or posted content, please see the TinBu Network Terms and Conditions. 

#### 2\. What organization is collecting the information?

When you register for a service within the TinBu Network, that information is generally collected and maintained solely by the TinBu Network unless specifically stated otherwise at the point of collection. If data is collected and/or maintained by any company other than TinBu, we will tell you at the point of collection. If you do not want to share your information with that company, you can choose not to use that service.

TinBu runs many promotions and sweepstakes across its Network. These promotions may be sponsored or co-sponsored by third-party companies. Data collected during a promotion is typically shared with the sponsor or co-sponsor. TinBu will inform you at the point of collection whether or not we are sharing your personal data as a result of your participation in a promotion or sweepstakes. If you do not want to have the TinBu Network share your data, you can choose not to participate in the promotion or sweepstakes.

Be aware that TinBu Network sponsors and other advertisers have links on the Network that take you to external sites. Some of these sites may collect personally identifiable information from you, and third-party advertising networks for TinBu may use cookies and Web beacons in their advertisements to collect certain information from you. Please see Section 7 of this policy for more information about advertising on the TinBu Network. While TinBu hopes that all third parties involved adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our users, the TinBu Network Privacy Policy does not cover third-party data collection practices and the TinBu Network does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties.

#### 3\. What are "cookies" and "Web beacons" and how does TinBu use them?

In addition to the personally identifiable information that TinBu actively collects when you register, we also collect anonymous information passively using cookies and Web beacons. This technology plays an important role in making the Internet work, but there is much confusion among Internet users about what cookies and Web beacons are and how they are used.

A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a Web site to the hard drive of your computer so that the site administrator may identify your computer and passively track its activities on the Web site. This unique number identifies your Web browser to our computer system whenever you visit one of the sites in the TinBu Network. A cookie will not allow a Web site to learn any personally identifiable information (such as your real name and address) that you have not otherwise disclosed.

Cookies allow TinBu to automatically remember your Web browser when you visit our Network of Web sites. To help serve you better, TinBu generally uses cookies to: 

  * **Allow us to deliver products and services more efficiently**. By storing certain registration and preference information on cookies or associating cookies with registration, preference or profile information stored on our computers, we can deliver products and services that use such information more quickly and efficiently for more users. This information is normally saved in an encrypted form that only TinBu can interpret.
  * **Prevent others from using your account**. On some TinBu Network sites, cookies help us efficiently determine that only one user is logged on under the same member name at a time.
  * **Measure statistics** such as audience size and traffic patterns. This information is only collected in aggregate form and will not be linked to your personally identifiable information.
  * **Display advertisements**. Cookies let us know whether a Web browser has seen a particular advertisement (so we can show you a variety of material) and count the number of advertisements displayed to a particular browser. We also use cookies to customize the advertising you see based on non-personally identifiable demographic information that you provide when you register. Third-party advertising networks for TinBu may issue cookies on the TinBu Network and other sites when serving advertisements. 

The use of cookies is an industry standard, and they are currently used on most major Web sites. It is possible to adjust your Web browser preferences to alert you when a cookie is sent to your hard drive, or to refuse cookies altogether. While TinBu does not require you to use cookies, keep in mind that certain sites and services will not function properly if you set your browser to refuse all cookies.

**Web beacons** , also known as clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs, are small image files that TinBu may place on Web pages and within Web-based email newsletters that we send. Working in conjunction with cookies, Web beacons allow TinBu to accurately count the number of unique users who have visited a specific page on the TinBu Network and the number of times those pages are displayed. We can also use Web beacons to let us know how many people opened a Web-based email newsletter. This information is only collected in aggregate form and will not be linked to your personally identifiable information.

Without cookies and Web beacons, it would be difficult for TinBu to know which services have a larger audience than others. Tracking audience size helps us to better understand when to launch new services and enhance the current offerings. Keep in mind that any image file on a Web page can act as a Web beacon. Third-party advertising networks for TinBu may use Web beacons in their advertisements.

Because Web beacons work in conjunction with cookies, you can prevent our Web beacon from collecting anonymous information by setting your Web browser to refuse all cookies or the TinBu Network cookie in particular. Web beacons are built into our Web pages, so non-functional Web beacons will continue to appear even if you refuse the TinBu Network cookie. 

#### 4\. How does the TinBu Network use the information it collects?

Any personally identifiable information you share with TinBu when registering for Products and Services at any of our Network sites is maintained and accessible only by TinBu unless specifically stated otherwise. TinBu requests information from its users so that users can enjoy customized experiences across the TinBu Network, including personalization services, interactive communications, online games and much more. Most of these Products and Services are available to you at no cost, and TinBu displays advertisements so we can continue to provide great content and services free of charge. We can also better prepare future content based on your interests. The following are examples of how the TinBu Network may use the information it collects: 

  * TinBu uses the information collected (both anonymous and personal) to personalize and enhance the content you see on the TinBu Network, such as news, stock portfolios, weather reports, sports scores, horoscopes, advertisements and more. In some cases, our Products and Services cannot work unless you have volunteered accurate information (for example, we need your valid ZIP Code to display weather conditions in your local area).
  * TinBu collects anonymous data and shares it with third-party advertisers in an aggregate form. We will disclose to those advertisers the numbers of TinBu users who have certain demographic characteristics and the number of those people who have seen and "clicked" on a particular display. We will also disclose to those advertisers the overall demographics available regarding who saw and "clicked" on their advertisement. In addition, we may disclose anonymous results from online surveys to third-party advertisers or to TinBu's product and service providers. No personally identifiable information will be disclosed as part of this process.
  * TinBu also uses the aggregate data to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our registered users and visitors, to measure user demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the TinBu Network, and to analyze how and where best to use our resources. Without such data, we would not know which parts of the TinBu Network are the most popular, and we would not be able to change and update the content and services appropriately. Please note that we may share this aggregate information with third-party companies.
  * TinBu collects an aggregate list of search terms from its HotBot and TinBu search services. This information is collected anonymously and used primarily for the purposes of product development, monitoring, and improvement, as well as targeted advertising. Please note, however, that we may share this anonymous information with third-party companies.
  * TinBu sometimes uses an individual registered user's data to "pre-populate" online forms that are displayed for the purpose of collecting additional individual data by the TinBu Network, selected third-party sites, and/or sponsors and advertisers.
  * TinBu may, from time to time, use your information to contact you about changes or enhancements to Products and Services on the TinBu Network, issues regarding your account, or TinBu Network Terms and Conditions violations or suspensions.
  * If you enter a sweepstakes or a contest on the TinBu Network, we will use the information you provided to contact you in the event you win.
  * If you told TinBu that you were interested in receiving special offers from select TinBu clients, TinBu or third parties on TinBu's behalf (i) will send you email and postal mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you, and (ii) may combine information we have about you with information we obtain about you from third parties for the purpose of providing you with more appropriate products, services, and offerings. If you do not wish to participate in this program, please follow the opt-out instructions set forth in Section 8 of this policy.
  * Subscription Customers: Your credit card information is used to collect your recurrent subscription fees for subscription services.
  * TinBu Family Membership Customers: Your credit card information is used to verify the age of a parent or guardian. The credit card will not be charged during the TinBu Family Membership registration process, and only the last 4 digits and a transaction number will be stored as proof of transaction. Click here for more information. 

#### 5\. With whom does the TinBu Network share the information that is collected?

Whenever you provide registration information on co-branded or private label sites, that data may be shared with the third-party company providing the service. You should make every effort to read the individual privacy policies of such third parties and make an informed decision on your own whether to continue based upon these sites' privacy practices and your own discretion. You may opt-out of sharing your information with such providers by choosing not to use that service or content.

When you find goods or services through TinBu Shopping, you submit data directly to the individual merchants from whom you order goods or services. Please review carefully the privacy policies of particular merchants that you access through TinBu Shopping.

In addition to finding co-branded and private label sites, you will find direct links on our site to sites offered by third parties. Some of these sites are authorized to use the TinBu Network brands and/or logos. No third-party sites are covered by this Privacy Policy. If you feel that a site using a TinBu Network brand and/or logo does not follow an acceptable privacy policy, please contact the TinBu Privacy Site Coordinator by email at [privacy@TinBu.com](mailto:privacy@TinBu.com).

TinBu may disclose information about individual users to third parties who agree to provide services to TinBu and who agree to maintain the confidentiality of such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. These third parties will provide a variety of services to TinBu, including, without limitation, processing and storing user information, helping to create new content and promotions for the TinBu Network, and sending or coordinating the sending of marketing communications that users have consented to receive. TinBu will disclose information about individual users to governmental or judicial authorities or law enforcement agencies, or to other individuals or entities in response to subpoena, court order, or other legal process. In matters involving a danger to personal or public safety, TinBu may voluntarily provide information to appropriate governmental authorities.

If you elect to receive TinBu Registration Offers during registration for the TinBu Network, TinBu will release personally identifiable information to the applicable sponsor or advertiser. Information released may include name, email address, postal address and other information supplied in the TinBu Network registration process. Please note that the sponsor or advertiser will not be bound by this TinBu Network Privacy Policy.

If TinBu is acquired by or merged with another company, TinBu may transfer personally-identifiable information about you to that company. TinBu will notify you in the event that your personally-identifiable information is transferred under these circumstances and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

If a third party acquires, or otherwise receives in a transaction with TinBu, one or more of the TinBu Products and Services, then TinBu will transfer personally-identifiable information about users of those Products and Services to the third party. The third party will handle the Products and Services in accordance with its own policies and procedures and not in accordance with TinBu policies and procedures. You will be notified if your personally-identifiable information is transferred under these circumstances by an email sent to the email address you provided or by a posting on the site that offers the relevant Products or Services.

TinBu Domains Customers: Users of TinBu Domains will be required to designate an administrative contact and, in some instances, a technical contact for the domain names they register. TinBu will assume that the TinBu member who registers for the TinBu Domains service will serve as these contacts, although users will have the ability to designate other contacts. TinBu will disclose the name, address, phone number, fax number, and email address of the administrative and technical contacts to TinBu's domain name provider, which in turn will make such information publicly available through an online WHOIS database. 

#### 6\. How can you access or edit your information?

The TinBu Network provides its registered users the ability to access and edit the personal information in their user profiles. You can access your user profile by following these steps: 

  * Go directly to this page. You will receive a prompt to log in to the Network with your TinBu Network Member Name and password. 
  * After you log in, you will be taken to the Membership Information page, which contains your user profile. If you see a field that needs to be updated, click the appropriate Edit button. 
  * Make the necessary changes and click the Update button to save your changes. 

#### 7\. What are the policies concerning advertising on the TinBu Network?

TinBu works with various 3rd party advertisers allowing certain ads to appear inside of TinBu.s web sites and modules. These advertisers can include AOL, Lycos, Yahoo!, Google, Advertising.com, and other approved online advertising groups. 

#### 8\. What is the opt-out policy for the TinBu Network?

You can opt out of sharing your personally identifiable information with any third-party service or content providers in any areas of the TinBu Network by choosing not to use such areas.

If you have a question about the TinBu opt-out process that is not answered here, please send an email to [privacy@TinBu.com](mailto:privacy@TinBu.com). 

#### 9\. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?

The TinBu Network has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. TinBu uses physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect any personally identifiable data stored on its computers. Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us. Credit card numbers used to purchase premium services are encrypted prior to transmission.

While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we take many precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.

You are ultimately responsible for the security of your TinBu Network ID and password. Please take care when using and storing them. TinBu recommends that you do not divulge your password to anyone. You should log out of your browser at the end of each computer session to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence, especially if several people have access to your personal computer or you are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

#### 10\. How does the TinBu Network comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)?

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998 provides safeguards to protect children who use the Internet by regulating the online collection of personal information from children under the age of 13. Because of these safeguards, children under 13 are not able to access or use all Products and Services on the TinBu Network. Parents of children under 13 can authorize their children to use some of our services by signing up for a TinBu Family Membership.

Parents can learn more about the TinBu Family Membership and obtain detailed answers about our compliance with COPPA by clicking here. 

#### 11\. What are the policies concerning software downloads?

TinBu may make certain software available for download. This software may be created by TinBu or by third party licensors. The software may be programmed to access our servers and/or third party servers in order for the software to operate and in order to check for program upgrades or enhancements. From time to time, new files may be added to your computer in order to upgrade the software or add new functionality to it. These changes may occur without notice to you. If at any time you wish to uninstall the software program, you may do so by following the instructions that accompany the software. Use of the software will be governed by a separate license agreement. 

#### 12\. Where is personally-identifiable information stored and processed?

Personal information collected by TinBu may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which TinBu or its agents maintain facilities. By using the TinBu Network, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. 

#### 13\. What you can do to better protect yourself on the Internet?

##### Know the risks.

Meeting new people in an online community (chat room, forum, newsgroup, message board, Web page, etc.) is one of the best things about the Internet, but you should always be careful about disclosing personal information such as an actual name, member name, email address, and so on. This information may be collected and used by others within the online community to send unsolicited email messages from other parties, outside the TinBu Network. Some of the messages you receive may be useful to you, but some may not. In an effort to curtail unsolicited email, TinBu blocks certain email addresses and domains from sending messages to email addresses at our domains. 

##### Educate yourself.

Search the Web for as much information as you can about how to protect your privacy. Look for a privacy policy on the Web sites you visit. A good place to start is TRUSTe -- an independent, non-profit organization with a mission to build trust and confidence in the Internet. The Federal Trade Commission has a great Web site with useful information on being a Savvy Internet Traveler along with other privacy initiatives. Additional privacy resources can be found at by clicking on any of the following links 

##### Department of Education: Parents Guide to the Internet

<http://www.ed.gov/pubs/parents/internet/>

##### Better Business Bureau (BBB)

##### Center for Democracy and Technology

<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/> \- Data Privacy  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/guide/> \- Guide to Online Privacy 

##### Direct Marketing Association (DMA)

<http://www.the-dma.org/>

##### Electronic Frontier Foundation - non-profit dedicated to protecting public interest in online privacy.

##### EPIC.org (Electronic Privacy Information Center)

##### Georgetown Internet Privacy Study

<http://www.msb.edu/faculty/culnanm/gippshome.html>

##### Net Nanny - child safety software that filters potentially harmful Web sites

<http://www.netnanny.com/>

##### NetCoalition.com

##### Network Advertising Initiative

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/>

##### Online Privacy Alliance

<http://www.privacyalliance.org/>

##### The Privacy Rights Clearinghouse

<http://www.privacyrights.org/>

##### Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"

While TinBu works hard to protect children on the sites within the TinBu Network, we cannot protect their privacy once they leave. Please teach children that they should not reveal their names or other personal information to anyone they encounter on the Internet. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any Web site without your knowledge and consent. Parents can also prevent or limit a child's access to inappropriate material on the Web by using commercially available parental control protections (such as computer hardware, software, or filtering services). Take advantage of the online resources for parents available on the TinBu Network, such as GetNetWise. 

##### Use PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) [http://www.pgp.com](http://www.pgp.com/) or another encryption program.

##### Contact Us

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to: [privacy@TinBu.com](mailto:privacy@TinBu.com)

##### Updates

The TinBu Network will update this policy from time to time so please check back periodically. When such changes occur, you will see the word "Updated" next to the Privacy Policy link on the front page of each site on the TinBu Network. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will prominently post such changes prior to implementing them.  |
